<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<application name="mar9res" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://isis.astrogeology.usgs.gov/Schemas/Application/application.xsd">
  <brief>
   Mariner 9 missing line repair program
  </brief>

  <description>
    <p>
      Subtracts residual component from Mariner 9 images using preflight 
      calibration data as well as inflight data.  The previous image must 
      immediately precede the input file (DAS count is 70 less), and should
      have had noise and reseaux removed.  Both input and output files are 
      8-bit.
      The Mariner 9 cameras were known to produce residual images (due to
      incomplete erasure of previous image) before flight and extensive
      calibration data was gathered.  These data were compressed into 
      several calibration files, one for each filter/camera combination.
      Data files for camera A, orange, green and 60 degree polarizing filters
      and for camera B have been created to date.  The input and previous DN
      values are used to interpolate between (or extrapolate from) calibration
      data values at each pixel to find the residual, which is then subtracted
      from the input image.  For more information see Herkenhoff et al., 1988
      in Icarus (in press).
    </p>
  </description>

  <category>
    <missionItem>Mariner 9</missionItem>
  </category>

  <history>
    <change name="Ken Herkenhoff" date="1986-06-26">
      Original version
    </change>
    <change name="Janet Barrett" date="2000-10-16">
      Port to Unix
    </change>
    <change name="Lucas Zadrozny" date="2022-08-14">
      Port to ISIS3
    </change>
  </history>

  <groups>
    <group name="Files">
      <parameter name="FROM">
        <type>cube</type>
        <fileMode>input</fileMode>
        <brief>
          Input image file name
        </brief>
        <description>
          The input Mariner 9 image must be 8-bit, and should have had
          reseaux and noise removed. If the file extension is omitted,
          then ".cub" will be assumed.
        </description>
        <filter>
          *.cub
        </filter>
      </parameter>
      
      <parameter name="PREVIOUS">
        <type>cube</type>
        <fileMode>input</fileMode>
        <brief>
          Previous image file name
        </brief>
        <description>
          The previous frame (if it exists) must have a DAS count
          (spacecraft time) that is exactly 70 less than that of the
          input image.  The previous image must also be 8-bit and
          should have had reseaux and noise removed. If the file
          extension is omitted, then ".cub" will be assumed.
        </description>
        <filter>
          *.cub
        </filter>
      </parameter>

      <parameter name="TO">
        <type>cube</type>
        <fileMode>output</fileMode>
        <brief>
          Output file name
        </brief>
        <description>
          The output image file will be 8-bit, with residual image
          removed. If the file extension is omitted, then ".cub" will
          be assumed.
        </description>
        <filter>
          *.cub
        </filter>
      </parameter>
    </group>
  </groups>

</application>

